Unknown: Gerard nos Trinity, the
chaos, dearest creature in
creation. Studying English
pronunciation, I will teach you
in my verse sounds like corpse,
core horse and worse,
it will keep you. Susie, busy,
make your head with heat, grow
dizzy, tear and I your dress,
you'll tear. So shall I O Hear
my prayer? Pray console your
loving poet, make my coat look
new dear, so
it just compare heartbeard and
herd dies and diet, Lord and
word, sword and sword retain in
Britain, mind the latter how its
written, made has not the sound
of bad say, said, pay, paid
late, but pled, now I surely
will not plague you with such
words as vague and aid you, but
be careful how you speak. Say,
break steak but bleak and streak
previous precious fuchsia via
pipe, snipe, recipe and Quire,
cloven, oven, how and Lo.
Script, receipt, shoe, poem, toe
here we say, devoid of trickery,
daughter, laughter and
Terpsichore, typhoid, measles,
topsels, isles, exiles, similes,
reviles, holy Holly, signal,
signing, Thames, examining,
combining scholar, vicar and
cigar, solar mica, war And far
from desire, desirable,
admirable from admirer, lumber,
plumber, beer but Brier,
Chatham, broom, renowned but
known. Knowledge, done but gone
and tone one, anemone, Balmoral,
kitchen, lichen, laundry,
Laurel, Gertrude, German, wind
and mind scene, Melpomene,
mankind, tortoise, turquoise,
chamois leather. Reading,
reading, reading, moss, gross
Brook, brooch, ninth plinth.
Billet does not end like ballet,
bouquet, wallet, mallet, chalet.
Blood and flood are not like
food, nor is mold like should
and would. Banquet is not nearly
parquet, which is said to rhyme
with darkey viscus, Viscount,
load and broad, toward to
forward to reward and your
pronunciations ok when you say
correctly. Croquet, rounded,
wounded, grieve and sieve,
friend and fiend, alive and
live, Liberty. Library, heave
and heaven. Rachel, ache.
Mustache, 11, we say hallowed
but allowed people, leopard Toad
but vowed. Mark, the difference
Moreover, between mover, plover,
Dover, leeches, britches, wise,
precise, Chalice, but police and
lice. Camel, Constable,
unstable, principal disciple.
Label, petal, penal and canal.
Weight, surmise, plat, promise,
pal, suite, ruin, circuit Condit
rhyme with shirkit and beyond
it. But it is not hard to tell
why. It's Paul mall, but pal Mel
mussel, muscular, jail, iron,
timber, climber, bullion, Lion,
worm and storm. Chase, chaos,
Chair, Senator, spectator, mare,
IV, privy famous clamor and
enamour rhyme with hammer,
pussy, hussy and possess desert
but dessert. Address golf, Wolf
countenance lieutenants hoist in
lieu of flags left pennants
river rival, Tomb, bomb, comb,
doll and roll and summoned home.
Stranger does not rhyme with
anger, neither does devour with
clangor soul, but fowl and
gaunt, but ant font front won't
want grand and grand shoes. Goes
those. No, you are wrong. This
is the plural of dough. Now
first say finger and then
singer. Ginger linger, real
zeal. Mauve, gauze and Gage.
Marriage, foliage, Mirage, age,
query does not rhyme with very
nor does fury sound like Barry,
dust, lost, post and Duff,
cloth, loath, job, job, Blossom,
bosom, oath, though the
difference seems little. We say
actual, but fiddle, seat, sweat,
chased, cast. Lee ate, height,
put not granite, but unite
reefer does not rhyme with
defer, Pfeffer does and Zephyr,
heifer, doll bull, Jeffrey
George et late, hint pint,
Senate, but sedate, scenic,
Arabic, Pacific Science,
conscience, scientific tour, but
hour and sucker four gas, alas
and Arkansas, see idea, Guinea
area, Sam, Maria, but malaria.
Youth, south, Southern, cleanse
and clean doctrine, turpentine,
marine, compare alien with
Italian, dandelion with
battalion, Sally with Ally, ye,
ye i a way, ki, ki, say, a ver
but ever. Fever, neither leisure
gain receiver, never guess it is
not safe. We say cars, valves,
half but rave heron, granary,
Canary, crevice and device and
airy face but preface, but
efface. Phlegm, phlegmatic as
glass, base, large, but target.
In, give, verging, ought out,
Joost and scour but scourging
ear but urn and wear and tear do
not rhyme with here, but air
seven is right, but so is even
hyphen, Ruffin, nephew, Stephen,
monkey, donkey, Clark and jerk,
ASP, grasp, wasp and cork and
work pronunciation, think of
psyche is a paling stout and
spiky. Won't it make you lose
your wits writing growths and
saying grits, it's a dark abyss
or tunnel strewn with stones
like roller gunnel Islington, an
Isle of Wight has if verdict and
indict. Don't you think so?
Reader, rather saying leather
bather, farther, finally, which
rhymes with enough though
through plow, cough, hock or
tuff, pick up as the sound of
cup, my advice is, give it up.
Do.