Dearest creature
in creation.
Study English pronunciation
I will teach you
in my verse sounds like
corpse core horse.
And worse I will
keep you susie busy.
Make your head with
heat, grow dizzy.
Tear in eye, your dress
will tear. So say.
Oh, hear my prayer.
Just compare heart,
beard and he dies.
And diet, Lord. And word.
Sword and sword, retain
and Britain mind the
latter, how it's written.
I surely will not
plague you with
such words as
plaque and age.
But be careful
how you speak.
Say break and stake,
but bleak and streak.
Cloven oven, how and
low script
receipt show poem
and toe here say
devoid of trickery,
Daughter laughter
and terps,
Typhoid, measles,
topsails,
aisles, exiles,
similes and reviles,
scholar vicar and cigar.
Solar mica war and far
on. E Anemone, balmoral
kitchen, lichen,
laundry, laurel,
Gertrude German,
wind and mind.
Seen Melpomene
mankind billet
does not rhyme with
ballet bouquet,
Wallet, mallet,
chalet, blood and
flood are not like food
nor is mould like.
And wood, viscous.
Viscount, load and
broad toward to
forward to reward and
your pronunciations.
Okay. When you correctly
say croquet, rounded,
wounded, grieve and sieve,
friend and fiend
alive and live Ivy.
Privy. Famous clamour and
enamor rhyme with Hammer,
River rival,
tomb bomb, comb,
doll and roll and
sum and home.
Stranger does not
rhyme with anger.
Neither does devour with
clangour souls
but foul haunt.
But ant font front want,
want grand and
grant shoes.
Goes does now first
say finger and
then singer Ginger
linger. Real zeal.
Move, gauze, gouge
and gauge marriage,
foliage, Mirage and age.
Query does not
rhyme with very,
nor does fury sound like
berry dust lost
post and D,
Cloth, loath,
job knob, bosom.
Transom oath.
Though the differences
seem little,
we say actual
but vital refer
does not rhyme with
defer. Fa does.
And Zephyr, Heifer, mint
pint, sent and sedate.
Dull Bull and
George et late.
Scenic Arabic, Pacific
science, conscience,
Scientific liberty,
library and heaven.
Rachel Aikmustache
11, we say
hallowed but allowed
people leopard towed.
But vowed. Mark
the differences
moreover between
mover cover, clover,
leeches, breeches wise,
precise chalice but
police and lice.
Camel constable, unstable,
principal disciple.
Label petal panel
and canal weight.
Surprise, plat promise.
Pal Worm and Storm
shares chaos.
Chair. Senator spectator.
Mayor to but our.
And succour. Four Gas.
Alas. And Arkansas
see Idea Korea area.
Psalm Maria but
Malaria Youth,
South Southern cleanse
and clean doctrine.
Turpentine marine.
Compare alien with
Italian dandelion
and battalion.
Sally with Ally I
why and key say over
but ever fever.
Neither leisure skin,
deceiver, heron,
granary, canary
crevice and
device and airy face.
But preface, not
efface phlegm
phlegmatic a
glass base large
but target in give verging
ought out joust and
scour scourging ear.
But urn and wear
and tear do not
rhyme with here.
But air seven is right,
but so is even hyphen.
Ruffin nephew,
Stephen, Monkey,
donkey Turk. And jerk
ask, grasp wasp
and pronunciation.
Think of psyche
is a paling,
stout and spiky, won't it?
Make you lose your wits?
Writing growths
and saying grits.
It's a dark
abyss or tunnel
strewn with stones
stowed Solace,
Gunnell, Islington,
and Isle of Wight,
Usif verdict and
indict finally,
which rhymes with
enough though through
plough or dough
or cough hiccup
has the sound of cup.
My advice is to give up
50 birds.